# RAMON E. MUNOZ

Phone: (951) 496-0337 | Email: RamonMunoz1027@Gmail.com | GitHub Profile: github.com/ramonemunoz

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A seasoned, versatile & enthusiastic Front-End Engineer, with 8+ years of experience. Brings an unwavering commitment to coding, launching and maintaining well-tested, secure websites, with expertise across multiple languages, frameworks & platforms.

Takes great pride in building performant, accessible websites that render high Core Web Vitals; skilled in implementing designs as closely as possible during the development process. Enjoys staying abreast of latest Front End practice & identifying optimal solutions according to current web standards.

### **SKILLS**

HTML | CSS | JS/ES6 | PHP | Node.js | Python | AWS (EC2, RDS, Lamda, Cognito, Elastic Beanstalk, S3, Code Commit) | Shopify/Liquid | APIs | MySQL/MariaDB | MongoDB | SASS | React.js | Gatsby.js | WordPress | WooCommerce | Git/Github | Gulp | npm | Composer

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Envoy – Irvine, CA 2020 – Present

#### **Front-End Engineer**

- Worked cross-functionally with creative directors, engineers, account & product managers to develop robust, scalable web solutions for clients.
- · Conducted sprint planning and presented feedback to product managers; collaborated closely with DevOps to build bespoke solutions for clients.
- Served as a versatile and adaptable subject matter expert; worked on several projects at different stages to drive completions ahead of deadline.
- Partnered with our internal React Native Engineer to build an app for an industry-leading golf company; worked across multiple APIs to bridge the company's several online platforms under one app; currently rated 4.3/5 on Apple App Store across 596 ratings.
- Worked on a headless Shopify & Gatsby e-commerce site; played a pivotal role in sustainably increasing the client's sales revenue by 20%.
  - o Resulted in client signing a retainer; selected to lead on this, providing time estimates & collaborating closely with producer to plan sprints.
  - o Successfully implemented a new development strategy for the client, adapting to outdated internal processes.
  - o In recognition of outstanding results on their B2C site, selected to work on their Pro site that handles B2B wholesale sales.
- Recently launched a new platform for BALA(<u>shopbala.com</u>) called <u>Balacize</u>, the whole application is run by APIs; played a key role in developing
  many components that hit the APIs then consumed the data to render the correct information.
  - o Grew to over 1000+ subscribers.
- Collaborated with our internal QA to deliver seamless functionality and intuitive design to top quality standards.

**3BLACKDOT** – Los Angeles, CA **2018 – 2020** 

### Senior Front-End Developer // Manager

- · Spearheaded key web projects from planning phases to launch, working closely alongside executives to bring strategic vision to life.
- Worked closely with the CEO and Art Director to code and launch the company's main corporate website; utilized the most advanced framework and hosting solutions to produce a globally user-friendly experience
- · Managed and gathered requirements from marketing and design to produce sites that delivered solutions for all teams.
- Championed the build of robust, fast and efficient sites, even during seasonal traffic spikes.
- Developed and implemented workflows to drive improvements in maintenance and collaboration processes.
- Cultivated and maintained key 3rd party relations; negotiated & implemented custom solutions from partners like YouTube, Vimeo, Kinsta & AWS.
- Oversaw the concentration of 28 disparate ecommerce websites into one centralized platform with a user-friendly back-end & easy maintenance.
- Created and successfully built the marketing website for a pioneering video game franchise that boasts a world-wide player base.

**530 Media Lab** – Cypress, CA **2016 – 2018** 

#### Front-End Developer

- Coded innovative websites in a fast-paced digital agency environment; worked closely with clients and executive team to bring visions to fruition.
- Worked collaboratively within a large team; utilized version control, project management applications, strict update policies and extensive QA.
- Successfully ported a Magento site to a custom Shopify e-commerce theme using Liquid and Shopify's API.
- Developed and updated fully responsive, custom Wordpress & Magento themes with 3rd party form integration & conversion-optimized layout.

### **EDUCATION**